Hi, in this lesson, give a welcome what DPPE is in Vinsore, our dwarves and how we can use it
quickly, understand any part of your database. Let's start what is DPPE. It's an AI power
documentation system built inside Vinsore. The coding environment we are using to this course.
It was originally created as a part of larger AI project called Devin and AI software
engineered, developed by the same team behind Vinsore. You can see in Devin as a very advanced
AI that can understand, edit and explain your codebase. Vinsore has now includes part
of the same technology, DeepVicky to make your own project easier to read and navigate.
DeepVicky works like smart documentation for your project that updates automatically.
It looks to record, understand how everything connects and creates some explanation for each part
of your code. So instead of sorting through the files and comments, manually, you can simply hover
over some variable of function name and get explanation written by AI. So now it's time to see
how it works inside of Vinsore. When you're reading your code, you can hover your mouse on any symbol
and it doesn't matter. It's variable, function or class name, and you will get some short
the AI generated explanation. So we can hover on a method on a class name and below you see
the explanation that this is based on this file. Constructor stores the password is this
that pass it check include lens, lowercase, uppercase, numbers into a password, and it returns
this props from the method. You can hover for example on a push method, what it does.
It depends your amounts to the end of the array and returns in your lens. This is a type
signature, this is where it was defined. For example, you can hover on, I don't know, a test method.
It checks through and against the regular expression or a tool in a Boolean result. So you can
hover on any method. You don't know what it does and it will explain to you how it works.
But in case you want to have a deeper explanation, for example, you have these check numbers.
Yeah, you see it's sliding. You have just a quick overview of what it does. But if you want
a bigger explanation, you can read more. Or you can just, if you use, for example, windows,
you can click control shift and click on the method name. Or if you're on mark, you can use
comment shift and click on the method name. And in the left sidebar, you will have a big page
with explanations. And for example, you see what is check numbers method does.
It evaluates whenever a password contains numeric characters.
It explains what is returns. You can read the definition. You can see the method implementation.
You can see more details. What every drop is returns means. You can also see some example usage.
For example, right here, you can use check numbers. And this is a test where you can see what you
can inspect. And you have some summary. You have also some notes about a check. So what regular
expressions it used, the check, and you can also see some other other methods can be useful.
So, and you can sample obclations. You can just click on them. For example,
how it interacts with common patterns, you just click. And you'll ask an AI in the right
shot. And it will give us some explanation.
So deep figure can also provide you some images, some diagrams,
some different formatted parts of code. As you see, you can easier understand how it works and
what it means. So let's not talk a bit how deep wiki works behind the scenes. So when you connect
the project to conserve, deep wiki automatically indexes your repository. It understands all your
code base. That means it scans all your files, figures how functions and components related
between each others and create some structured wiki, a kind of internal website for your code.
It can include some architecture, diagrams, the commutation pages for key folders,
and some links for specific sorts of files. This system can help you
helps an AI to answer some questions more accurately when you ask something about them. And you
also have a possibility to customize deep wiki. So let me find the another resource you can find
in the resources for this lesson. It did pick a documentation from Devin. So we can read here
much more. How it works and maybe we'll do it quickly overview how we can customize it.
If you have a specially large project, you can guide deep wiki using some simple configuration
file which called dot_daven slash wiki dot_json. I will show you. So this is this file you can use
and this is the name of the file. So dot_daven is the folder where you can put it and this is a file.
So you have some configuration format. It should leave in your main order. And for example,
you can use it to tell deep wiki what to focus on. For example, if you want to focus on some
specific pages, you can also mention them. You can define your own pages and mode.
And let them as priorities for the deep wiki. And it can help to understand your good base better.
So for example, you see here is a wrap on mode section. You just can add a content, what it's about,
what it contains, and what you'd like to show in deep wiki. And here you can create a separate
pages. For example, if it wasn't covered, you can mention for example, create a page for the
components over you. You can add a purpose, what it is. You can also make some hierarchy.
Right here, you can just mention the parent, for example, the authentication system. It's a parent.
You can also mention an altar. And for each page, you can mention the titles, the purpose,
the parents, the page note, additional notes specific about this page. So you can also have
some validation limits is how much the characters you can use per note, per title, etc.
And you can find more examples right here. Let me explain you why it's really important to use
because deep wiki can save you a lot of hours when you try to understand the code base or for example,
when you're trying to implement a new feature or pick some bug, you can just hover on methods
faster and understand how it works. You can use it and jump it between files. It will show you the
all relations, all the information you need right here. So it will help you to learn some projects,
some information much faster. And so, now you know how what is deep wiki, how it works,
that you can hover on any character you want in see an explanation. And I hope after this
lesson, you will be able to explore any code base with more confidence, because this feature,
you'll always be there and explain you everything ever seen as you need. Okay, see you in the next
That's the best one.